A Guide to the Haigh Jamgochian Papers, circa 1930-2006
Library of Virginia
- Series V. Rockfalls School, circa 1971-1974., Extent: 1 box. (Box 30)
  This series contains information on the private school operated by Haigh Jamgochian in the early 1970s during the "Massive Resistance" movement in Virginia. Also included is information on art classes taught by the architect as a means of income. Included is information on the building; photographs of students, teachers, and activities; and examples of student work.
  - Advertising, circa 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Annual [Yearbook], circa 1973. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Building, 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    See also OVERSIZE folder.
  - Building, 1971. (Map-case 20, Drawer 13, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1972. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, circa 1971-1974. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Field Trip Film, circa 1972. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Super 8mm film.
  - Forms, circa 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Minutes,, 1974. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Photographs,, circa 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Photographs [Service Copies], circa 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Service copies for original photographs damaged by water.
  - Photographs [Damaged Originals], circa 1971-1972. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    Originals damaged by water. Do not serve.
  - Photographs, 1974. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1971-1978. (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Art and Artifacts, 1935-1955., Extent: 3 folders. (Box 31)
  - Figure in Relief, circa 1935. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Height: 10 in., Width: 9-1/2 in.; Materials: Copper framed in tin.
  - Painting, circa 1952. (Map-case 40, Drawer 10, Folder 1)
    Height: 27 in., Width: 54 in.; Materials: Acrylic on pressed board.
  - Painting, circa 1955. (Map-case 40, Drawer 10, Folder 2)
    Height: 14 in., Width: 43 in.; Materials: Acrylic and unknown materials on pressed board.
- Series VII. Additional Donations, circa 2006., Extent: 1 architectural model.
  This series was created in anticipation of additional donations to this collection.
  - Unnamed Church Building for Rockfalls property, circa 2006., Height: 25 in., Width: 22 in.; Materials: cardboard, plastic, wood, metal, paper, fabric. (Map-case 23 (top))